MEZEKR WELDU Full-stack web developer

in LinkedIn GitHub Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-stack JavaScript developer with expertise in developing responsive websites, web apps, and mobile apps. Possesses two years' experience in data processing and machine learning, complemented by transferable skills in software development, problem solving, and collaborative teamwork. Committed to partnering with clients to transform their ideas into reality and overcome complex challenges.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-end: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS, ReactJS, Angular, Redux, AJAX, jQuery, Material, SASS,

Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Jest, Cucumber, Puppeteer, UI/UX, User Flow, Wireframes

Back-end: NodeJS, Express, SQL, MongoDB, RESTful API, JSON, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Django ...

Dev Tools: Python, AWS, Git, GitHub, Docker, CI/CD, Linux (Ubuntu), Vite, Webpack, Jira, Postman...

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer 03/2023 - 08/2023

Pulsotronic GmbH & Co. through FERCHAU GmbH, Niederdorf / Chemnitz

- Designed and implemented a software module for data pre-processing and signal analysis resulted more accurate frequency analysis
- Applied pre-processing, statistical and frequency analysis to the raw data provided to identify trends
- Tech-Stack: Python, Pandas, Scipy, Librosa, Git, Gitlab, Jupyter Notebook, Plotly, Jira

Python Developer as Research & Teaching Assistant TU Bergakademie Freiberg, Freiberg (Saxony)

12/2020 - 06/2022

- Developed the github2pandas_manager package to optimise retrieving open source repository data from GitHub using a REST API.
- Developed an algorithm to bypass the GitHub Restful API rate limit to optimise data processing and retrieval time.
- Collaborated on data analysis to research collaborative programming learning between computing and noncomputing students.
- Tech-Stack: Python, Pandas, Git, GitHub, GitHub REST-API, Jupyter Notebook

Information Communication Technology Teacher Sembel secondary school (Sss), Asmara

09/2013 - 07/2014

- Expanded and maintained the school's local area network, providing more staff and students with access to e-learning resources
- Improved learning outcomes by expanding access to IT resources and e-learning materials for staff and students by 40%, resulting in a better educational experience

SELECTED WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

MeziFlix-app (Back-end) | Source Code

Nodejs | Express | MongoDB | Docker

- Crafted business logic for the server-side application, providing an API for easy storage and management of movies and user data.
- Implemented the RESTful API using Node.js, Express, MongoDB and integrated Passport for authentication and JWT for authorization.
- Tech-Stack: JavaScript, Nodejs, Express, MongoDB Atlas, mongosh, REST-API, JSON Insomnia, Git, GitHub, Docker

MeziFlix | Web app | Source Code

ReactJS | Bootstrap | SASS

- Developed a responsive ReactJs single page application that allows users to search and view movie info. Users can also create/edit/delete an account and add/remove movies to/from favorites
- Implemented the RESTful API provided by the "MeziFlix-app" backend App
- Tech-Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, Material, Git, GitHub, RESTful-API, Docker

Mezimeet App | *Website* | *Source Code*

ReactJS | Jest | Puppeteer | Jest

- crafted a PWA that allows users to discover events in cities around the world, view event details and filter events by city or number
- Developed applying TDD methodology, including unit, integration and end-to-end testing
- Implemented OAuth 2.0 with Google using AWS Lambda serverless function, Google Calendar API to retrieve upcoming events
- Tech-Stack: JavaScript, React, CSS, SASS, Jest, Puppeteer, Cucumber, Recharts

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate CareerFoundry, Berlin (Remote)

12/2023 - 10/2024

- 900+ hours of immersive, project-based training that prioritizes best practices, guided by an industry-leading tutor and mentor
- Focused on JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS and frameworks / libraries including React, Angular, Nodejs, Express, MongoDB and React Native for mobile app development
- Developed over 6 interactive and responsive web applications by implementing engaging UX/UI design

Master of Science in Applied Computer Science TU Bergakademie Freiberg, Freiberg (Saxony)

10/2019 - 09/2022

• Focus areas: Artificial Intelligence, Distributed systems, Virtual reality

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering Eritrean Institute of Technology, Mai-Nefhi

09/2008 -07/2013

• Focus areas: Software Engineering, Networking, Embedded Systems

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATION

Languages: German, fluent written and spoken (C1)

English, fluent written and spoken

Driver's license: European type B